Paul R. Nguyen

nguyen.paul.r@gmail.com | 773-865-0462 | Chicago, Illinois

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/paul-nguyen-740051138/

GitHub: https://github.com/pnguven6910 | Website: https://pnguven6910.github.io/

SUMMARY

Developer with multiple years of experience in Retail Sales. Demonstrated history of working with a multitude of clientele with excellent time management skills, written and verbal communication, customer service, business acumen, and multitasking. Employee Training, Retail Sales, Full-Stack Development, JavaScript, React, NodeJs, HTML, & Bootstrap. Strong sales professional and graduated from Northwestern University.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office | Customer Service | HTML5 | CSS3 | Bootstrap | JavaScript | jQuery | Firebase | Node.js | MySQL | APIs | Media Queries | Handlebars | AJAX | JSON | GeoJSON | Reactjs | Responsive Design | Git | GitHub

PROJECTS

Lets GO (Team Lead)

https://github.com/pnguven6910/lets-go | https://glacial-waters-54685.herokuapp.com/

- A Cycling app to help cyclists find safer alternative routes throughout their city and allowing users to post points of interest by clicking/tapping on the map.
- Built using Bootstrap, React, CSS, Leaflet, react-leaflet, GeoJSON, and MongoDB Atlas for data storage.

Choose Your Coding Adventure

(Front/Back End)

https://github.com/thompson-1657/create_your_own_adventure | https://enigmatic-badlands-87608.herokuapp.com/

- A choose your own adventure app that allows the user to sign up for an account, make a character and progress through the story.
- Built using JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Handlebars, nes.css, Sequelize, Express, Passport, and MySQL for data storage.

EXPERIENCE

05/2017 - Present

General Manager, Vape312 Lakeview - Chicago, IL

- Direct and manage our organization's business activities and to develop and implement effective business strategies and programs such as our happy hour deal which boosted our sales 15%.
- Allocating budget resources, formulating policies, coordinating business operations, monitoring and motivating staff, managing operational costs, ensuring good customer service, improving administration processes, engaging with vendors, hiring and training employees, and monitoring financial activities.
- Maintaining relationships with clients, generating new business by having social media contests which boosted sales 30%, increasing staff productivity, ensuring sustainability by pricing items at margins for maximum profit, and meeting business objectives.

05/2014 - 08/2016

Front Desk, LA Fitness - Chicago, IL

- Answers questions and manages check-in and check-out procedures for existing members and guests.
- Answer phone calls from client prospects or members seeking information about gym hours, available equipment, classes, and other items.
- Daily pool PH checks.

11/2014 - 06/2015

Customer Service Rep, Mariano's – Chicago, IL

- Count money in cash drawers at the beginning and end of shifts to ensure that amounts are correct and that there is adequate change.
- Resolve customer complaints, guide them and provide relevant information.
- Pleasantly deal with customers to ensure satisfaction.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp | Northwestern University | Chicago, IL | 2021